Emmet Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Sep 13, [1936] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (at Great Enton, Witley, Surrey) - Subjects: Roger and a man named Irving; Hitler; Bobby and politics--opinion on Russia and Stalin; tea at the Masseys'-- Geoffrey Kerr; Mrs. Massey appreciates Lybba; Madeleine; Lydia Sherwood to interview celebrities such as Fred Astaire; looked for Sarah Curran painting at Lady Mayo's; Bobby found papers of John Wilkes Booth's ancestors at Drury Lane Theatre
Sep 19, [1936] - To: Jane - From: Lydia (in U.S.) - Subjects: bad voyage on the Queen Mary; Eileen Tone; Helen Morgan; saw Showboat starring Paul Robeson;Georgie Hunter was married in Bay's house; Mr. Monod pursuing a scientific career in France; saw article on Korda; Emmet show at Arden Gallery
Sep 22, 1936 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Ros went to ship to meet Lydia; Bob and family sailing; Lydia Sherwood practically an editor--her article on Korda; Bobby says everything settled with the Lord Chamberlain; Arch enrolled at Columbia Law School
Sep 28, [1936] - To: Lydia - From: Mary Whitehouse - Subject: Sylvia's portait for Emmet show at Arden
Sep 30, 1936 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lydia S. in Detroit; carnage in Spain
Oct 22, [1936] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Jacquot came to his senses; Kreisler-- used Theo Hawley's seats; Bay; the Lunts; Emmet show at Arden--Benny's picture by Lybba; Marc Connelly; Lydia paints the little white mouse boy; Mary Sherwood (Sr.) jealous of Madeleine; Romeo and Juliet movie--Norma Shearer and Leslie Howard; Gielgud's Hamlet; Dooley's sculpture Mother and Child; the Roosevelt vs. Landon election; Bob's show; Wilfrid has abdominal operation
[Nov 1936] - To: Lydia - From: Harriet Aldrich - Subject: saw Alexander's portrait in the studio
Nov 7, [1936] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Posie fell again; Langers sails to Arizona via Panama Canal; Roger's opera Julia; Mrs. Griswold flew in the Hindenberg
Nov 17, 1936 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Posie's bandaged foot; Caroline Phillips wants portrait of son; Leslie's painting in show; Aldriches love portrait of boys; Lydia's pains due to fall on rocks; Roger's opera; Bobby at art show; the Lunts--Lynn's new accent criticised by Noel Coward; Greta and Gable in film version (of Idiot's Delight)
Nov 30, 1936 - To: Jane - From: Lydia Sherwood - Subjects: Gielgud's Hamlet; Arch likes Gretchen Ridder; Jim Townsend's first job as stock runner; success of Emmet exhibition--Dooly's works; Jane and Wilfrid to visit U.S.?; Uncle Bob's death
[Fall 1936] - To: Wilfrid - From: Posie - Subjects: Kate Gibson; Matilda Brownell; Nite is ill; the King and Mrs. Simpson; Roger's opera; Rembrandt
Dec 3, [1936] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Edward VIII; Emmet exhibition; Frank's aunt Mrs. Kissel; Kate Schley; Eliot Wadsworth wants portraits by Lydia and Bay; Lydia mad at Cortissoz's review of Jane; Maud Hill; Eleanor Baldwin; Winty in the County Council's office; Leslie Howard in Hamlet
Dec 12, 1936 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Marga's boy; the Schleys bought Jane's painting; Lydia and Bay got good orders; try to get olive tree sketch from Eddie-- Jane lent it to Lybba; Spain; Hitler; Edward VIII's farewell
Dec 29, 1936 - To: Posie - From: Phil - Subjects: winter sports; Emmet exhibiton
Dec 29, [1936] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia paints Mrs. Wadsworth (her sister went to school with Mrs. Simpson); Bob and Mad's Christmas party with Mary--June Walker; Lunts not at party; Elsie Colt broke hip; Susina and Walter Pitkin
Dec 30, 1936 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Gordon Forbes visits the Arthur Jrs. for Xmas; Bob and Madeleine; Grenville and Pauline sailed for Princess Juliana's wedding; the poor King's broadcast; Roger's opera a success
Jan 14, 1937 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Florence will be in U.S. in a week; Minnie Forbes; Bobby doing a "Marco Polo film", Idiot's Delight movie, and 3 films for Garbo: Conquest, Napoleon, and Mara Walewska; Dooly's statue; Roger; the Dana Gibsons (Kate and Irene Gibson); Mrs. Simpson with Lady Astor to coronation; Stevenson quote
Jan 14, 1937 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: payment from Arden Gallery; Lydia paints Mrs. Wadsworth; Bay's house; Lydia's opinion of Copley; Rose and Les know Gretchen Ridder; Lydia to paint children in Princeton; Jane should come in August; Nancy found Julia W. on floor
Jan 31, 1937 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Flagstad and Melchior on radio; Elma's teeth; Granny Noyes is 90; Ursula Morgan, Pierpont's niece; sad about Phyllis Brand; Yehudi Menuhin; Idiot's Delight; the Lunts; death of Tonks; Lyd paints Mrs. Wadsworth whose first husband was Guy Skull painted by Bay; Lydia does Madeleine's portrait
Feb 1, 1937 - To: Lydia - From: Lynn Fontanne - Subject: Amphitryon costumes; Roger Quilter; Bob's picture; Henry Tonks' death
Feb 12, 1937 - To: Lydia - From: Lynn Fontanne - Subjects: Bobby's sketch; Roger's photo; Jane and Wilfrid to visit U.S.
Feb 18, 1937 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Jane and Wilfrid to visit U.S.; Sybil Jay (daughter of Delancy Jay and Eliz. Morgan) married Francis Kinnicutt; wedding of Hope and Jim; Bob and Madeleine in Hollywood for films Idiot's Delight, Marco Polo (Gary Cooper), and Napoleon for Garbo; Bobby's quote: "a director is someone who knows what he wants but does not know how to pronounce it"; Bobby happy that Noel Coward discouraged the Lunts from doing the play in London
Feb 18, [1937?] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: finished Mrs. W.; saw Garbo in Camille; saw Duse as Camille; disliked John Barrymore in Romeo and Juliet; disliked movie Rembrandt; Lydia met Maurice Evans after performance of Richard II; Florence's break with Langers--she went to New Orleans and Mexico; Lynn writes of Bobby's Xmas drawing when 9 years old; Bob and Madeleine in Hollywood--dust storms out west; wedding of Jim and Hope; (drawing of bridesmaid dresses)
Mar 3, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Ray Massey to Hollywood for Prisoner of Zenda; Bob and Madeleine; DeWolfe Gibson and Helen and had hoped for Dana and Irene Gibson; a Jew named Scholle married Eleanor which at first horrified Bay, Rosina and Leslie; Nite well again; Bobby back from Hollywood-Idiot's Delight movie; Bobby loves Garbo in Camille; Temple Biddle's new baby Nicholas Biddle Edmonds; Ray Massey to have Alfred's part in London production of Idiot's Delight next autumn; Bobby has sinus and neuralgic pain; Arthur Sherwood Jr.'s play Celestial Holiday to open in St. Louis
Mar 26, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby's Road to Rome notices from Jane; Bobby doesn't want to be at coronation; Bob and Madeleine to travel in Italy and Greece, and back to England; Bob's play about Abraham Lincoln; Jane and Wilfrid's visit; Cynthia will take little Mary to England; Posie fell on church steps
Apr 1, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia paints Hope; Helen Gibson; Helen Hayes as Victoria; sympathy about Peter Harrison--Wilfrid's portrait of him; Dooly's beau Fred Jackson is a grandchild ofEmily and Ned Potter; Langers' life is sad
Apr 6, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: death of Peter Harrison; Arthur back with photos of his play Celestial Holiday--starring beautiful girl from Busch family; Elsie in Paris; Road to Rome is in London
Apr 13, 1937 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Posie's fall; Jane and Wilfrid's visit; Ros painting Hope; Posie to be a great-grandmother in 8 months; Korda's film Lady Jane Gray; Irene Gibson back from London
Apr 24, [1937] - To: [Jane] - From: Lydia - Subjects: psychics; Bob and Madeleine to Greece; Bay wants Gary Cooper to portray Lincoln;John Barrymore
May 21, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: portrait of 3 heads; Langers in U.S.; Massey couldn't be as good as Alfred Lunt; Roger
May 22, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Maud Hill called; coronation on radio; Lydia paints Henry Paige; Jane to visit; Roger's new place; Katsie in Reno--she's in love with John Churchill
May 27, [1937?] - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Lew Wallace against Lydia's rights; Alice and Bill James; Eleanor and Mr. Scholle; Wilfrid and Academy show
Jun 5, 1937 - To: Lydia - From: Bernard Peyton - Subject: bill for portrait
Jun 12, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Posie's 2 falls--she was ill while with Jane last Sept.; Lydia's portrait of Mrs. Sheldon; letter from Bobby in Athens--Hope Cynthia and Mary have arrived; Lydia Sherwood's beau Williams; the Sydney Howards bought Tyringham place; Sydney wanted to produce Dodsworth in Berlin; Sinclair Lewis here as Riggs patient
Sep 13, [1937] - To: Posie - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia paints baby; Susie wrote about the Emmet show; Leslie won prize; lovely picture of Lynn arrived on ship; Lydia's teeth
Oct 7, [1937] - To: Lydia - From: Herman (with G. E., Erie, Pa.) - Subjects: his daughter's wedding; Lydia Sherwood and Lew Williams on honeymoon
Oct 20, 1937 - To: Metropolitan Museum of New York - From: ? - Subject: offer of Rosina Sherwood paintings
Oct 24, 1937 - To: Lydia - From: Langers - Subject: Florence's altered feelings
Nov 3, 1937 - To: Lydia - From: Herman - Subject: worry about Uncle Bill who is 78 years old
[Dec 1937] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Uncle Bill's health; Martha Bacon Whitney and Elizabeth Jay; Betsy's book; Bay and Dooly; Lydia paints Proctor girl
Dec 13, 1937 - To: Jane and Wilfrid - From: Lydia Sherwood - Subjects: New Yorker job starts June 1; wants to go to Europe; Arch is Chief Justice of Law School; Dooly entered her statue in the Metropolitan Life Insurance Building at World's Fair; Idiot's Delight
Dec 14, [1937] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bob and Madeleine; Posie read Lincoln play for her birthday
Dec 22, 1937 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Winty and daughter Daphne to Marion's for family reunion; Bob and Madeleine went to Polly Damrosch Howard's Christmas party
Jan 8, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Lyman Beecher Stowe - Subject: tickets for his lecture
Jan 11, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Roger and Penny Whitman (she has broken leg and is expecting in 8 weeks; Betsy Jay's book about Steven Jay's one man show
Jan 18, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: sherry party at No. 11 Downing Street-- Mrs. Chamberlain (painted by Wilfrid) and Lady Cunard; Bay; Langer's problems; Bobby in Hollywood-Idiot's Delight; New Deal; yman Beecher Stowe's lecture; Roosevelt wrote beautiful note to Susie
Jan 18, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Posie x-ray--improved since Jane's visit; Bob and Madeleine's impersonation game; Arthur and Ev's silver wedding anniversary; Ray Massey showed the Abe Lincoln play to business manager; Lydia's picture finished; Aurore (Ora) Dunnett
Feb 3, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Hopie and Jim's baby; Posie does portrait of baby; Ros does portrait of Princeton child; Bob and Madeleine went to California; Flo's problems
Feb 3, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie, Lilli, Maria; Herm and "his new Jewess"; Posie's drawing of Jim and Hope's baby
[Feb 1938] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Lewis Williams tells about Lydia Sherwood (Williams)' baby boy; Jerry works for Mr. Gallup; Thornton Wilder portraying stage manager in Our Town; Wilder came to tea
Feb 11, 1938 - To: Posie - From: Phil - Subject: Elsie doing artwork
Feb 15, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: poor old Bill; Susie's political views
Feb 21, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: visited Bill; Bay; Penny's cast is off
Feb 22, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: childrens' orchestral concerts; the Lunts; Roger lives at Melina Ct. NW8 until March
Feb 29, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Elma Marsh can't play cello now; Mark sings next month
Mar 1938] - To: Miss Wedgwood Stanton - From: Ruth(in Burma) - Subject: description of travels
Mar 8, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Winty and Marion separating
Mar 9, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Ruth (in Burma) - Subject: description of travels
Mar 10, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: failure of Richard Whitney, Eddie Morgan's partner (Richard is brother of George Whitney, J. P. Morgan's partner); Bobby took little Mary to DC-- saw White House--FDR wants to see him; Nancy Whitehead; Zebbie in The Seagullwith the Lunts
Mar 10, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: failure of Richard Whitney and Co.; Winty's wife Marion left with the baby; Lydia finished painting the old North Carolinian, now will paint 3 year old twins
Mar 21, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Mabel LaFarge; Roger and Mark for dinner; premiere of Idiot's Delight; Geoff; visited Kenwood; discussions of war; Riette Cochran Baillee and Winty Milford (these Cunards went to Vienna for Nazi triumph); Susie pleased Franco won?; Cecile expecting
Mar 21, 1938 - To: Cynthia - From: Pauline Davis (Morgan Art Gallery of Washington) - Subject: loved portrait of her daughter Betsy
Mar 25, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Idiot's Delight well received in London; Roger; Bobby quote; film Northwest Passage
[Mar 1938] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: young George Whitney (Martha Bacon's boy) engaged; Bobby working on Northwest Passage
Mar 30, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Penny had a boy Mar 28
Apr 1, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Ralph P. Hanes - Subject: loves portrait
Apr 5, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: state of the world; Zena got scholarship; Lydia criticized FDR for accepting immigrants; Lydia paints twins
Apr 11,1938 - To: Lydia (214 E. 70th) - From: Jane G. Hanes - Subject: her father's portrait
Apr 12, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subject: Idiot's Delight with Bredins; Ray Massey and Tamara Geva
Apr 13, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bob sails in a week--syndicate of writers, a play production company--Bobby, Sidney Howard, Maxwell Anderson, Sam Behrman and Elmer Rice-Abe Lincoln will be their first--looking for a theater in DC; Bay; Phil, Zena, and Philby toured DC
May 3, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lunts on Normandie to Europe; Lydia finishedtwins; Inglis Griswold--engaged in Communism business--borrows pictures from Lydia and Bay; Lydia saw Duveneck paintings at the Whitney; Katsie and John Churchill; Lydia fell; will paint the 3 Robert Winthrop girls; Hollins/Elkins woman wants portrait of 3 girls in June
May 31, [1938?] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's health; Lydia paints a baby; Langers arrives tomorrow; Thomas is attache to the Irish Free State ambassador to Vatican; Mox Kobbe's birthday June 1; Mrs. Nick Brady, who married Irish diplomat McCauley, is sister of Francis Garvan whose children Lydia painted-Mrs. Brady ordered 3 portraits and got Lydia Mrs. Hoover
Jun 7, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: is Lydia Sherwood (Williams) back from Europe?; Langers to visit Lydia; Lydia ill
Jun 9, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: June and Geoff Kerr in Stockbridge theatre--Cowles Strickland is manager of the Playhouse and has part for Cynthia; Bobby in England; Betsy in The Late Christopher Bean
Jun 18, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia Sherwood Williams - Subjects: home with sunburn; Dooly, Cynthia, Ginny, Lydia, and Arch to visit Jane; Wilfrid's show; Wilfrid's nude in Punch
Jun 22, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Jane's trip to East Lyndbourne--Wilfrid fishing; Jane saw Don Giovanni; Robert Emmet and Irish heroes; Langers and Flo breakup
Jul 17, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Roger and Susie - Subjects: will move to 23 Acacia Rd. NW8 in Aug; saw Amphitryon together and Café Royal; loved Idiot's Delight; Jane saw Ireland
Jul 18, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Grandpa born in Cork; Emmets show at Arden Gallery; Susie sang at the Rice's; Mrs. Paul Warburg wanted to come to party, but the Metzes (Hitlerites) were there; Phil to manage Dedham Country and Polo Club; Lilli and Susie; sites of Emmet homes in Dublin
Aug 3, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subject: Jane's letters from Ireland; tea for Alice Burr; Susie; Hopey and Jim arrive; Winty's divorce; Bob and family landed in U.S.
Aug 11, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bobby and Madeleine to visit Woollcott's Island in Vermont for advice re Abe Lincoln; skunk named Aroma; Wagner music festival; Susie made a professional-looking coat; Maud Howe Eliot's book about her Uncle Sam Ward (Alida's grandfather); Chauncey Depew
Aug 24, 1938 - To: Posie - From: Edith Fiske Bradford - Subjects: want Phil and Elsie's address in Cannes and to teach in Pau next winter
Aug 31, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie; Bob and Madeleine; Cynthia portrayed Aunt Gardner in Pride and Prejudice; little Mary works under Lovey Paige; Mussolini ousting Jews; Bobby gave Lew Martin a good part in Abe Lincoln; Bay painting--John Rand is a beauty; Lydia took one of Bay's paintings off wall; Guy with Jane
Sep 3, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (73 Cheyne Walk) - Subjects: Guy's mother dying; Jane goes to Cannes; Roger; Jewish question; Dr. Rudolph Stern; Cecile and new son Esme; the Jacquots; Wilfrid's Uncle Ernest is 91
Sep 15, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Lydia's opinion of Eddie Morgan just after Alty's death; Hope walked out on Jim; Posie does a watercolor of Zena
Sep 16, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: Lydia Sherwood Williams' letter; Barbara's baby; Roger performed in Lincolnshire with Myra Varney, sister of Harriet Cohen; Jessie Snow; May Mukle
Oct 5, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Maria - Subject: book of prophecy of the pyramid--applied to the world situation
Oct 5, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Bob's DC telegram--success of Abe Lincoln and Massey; Susie with Lydia?; Gerry and Kate
Oct 11, [1938] - To: Lydia - From: Jane -Subjects: Wilfrid to Richmond with watercolor; hate Germans' actions on Jews; Violet Ormond bought a Lucien; Florence Hooton the cellist (married to David Martin, a Canadian violinist); friends of Fred Grinke; King and Queen to visit the U.S.
[Oct 11, 1938] - To: Jane - From: Posie -Subjects: Bobby and Madeleine--play opens on Saturday; Dorothy Thompson
Oct 14, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane (Paulton Sq., behind 73 Cheyne Walk) - Subjects: Listers visiting; Elena, Elma Marsh and Peter; Barbara posed in hat that made Queen laugh; London war preparation; Abe Lincoln; film Pygmalion starring Leslie Howard and excellent girl as Eliza; Roger
Oct 20, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: hurricane; LaFarges; Abe Lincoln and Massey; Mark; Susie must visit London on way home; Anne Balfour and family
Oct 22, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Abe Lincoln opening; the Lunts; Lydia paints Lee Proctor; Lydia's will; Ethel Folsom; Bob and Madeleine couldn't go to White House so Eleanor Roosevelt sent letter; Dorothy Thompson and Sidney Howard--Polly had baby
Oct 28, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Abe Lincoln in NY; Anne and Stephen Balfour; Mondi looks ill; Susie with Lydia?; Grinke trio; Wilfrid does portrait of young woman next week
Oct 29, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Hitler and world scene; Gary Cooper may do Abe Lincoln in film- possibly through Playwright's Producing Company--their 2nd production was Knickerbocker Holiday by Maxwell Anderson; Sidney and Polly Howard took Dorothy Thompson to see it; Lydia does Proctor portrait
[Oct/Nov 1938] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Elmer Rice directing Abe Lincoln; Dooly is with Posie; Donald Ryan in hospital with nervous breakdown; Posie does watercolor of Zena; Cecilia Beaux had cataract removed
Nov 4, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia Sherwood Williams (145 E. 74th) - Subjects: London to be bombed; Lydia with Jane last spring; Judge Klein lent her his horse; Jim and Hope to divorce; Abe Lincoln; Langers is ill
Nov 11, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Archie ill--home from Law School; Sir Alfred Booth; Abe Lincoln--Massey; Lydia paints Bea Proctor; Langers; John Powell concert; Olin Downes; Helen Griffiths
Nov 18, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: heard from Lucien about selling painting to Violet Ormond; private view at Portrait Society
Nov 20, [1938] - To: "Young Zanuck" - From: Jane - Subjects: not sure Lucy back from U.S.; Dyson turned up; Mike Harrison; Wilfrid and Dorothy vs Jane Erin and Sleator in tennis; Wilfrid's sore arm; Mark's concert; Louis and Dinah; Bancel's father's death; Cecile Mondi and Francis; Nora Furman; Dartington Hall; Violet Ormond
Nov 24, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Roger Quilter - Subject: thanks for lovely weekend
Nov 25, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Arch feels better; a year since Jane left; Frick girl; saw Elmer Rice's play American Scene in Boston; Abe Lincoln
Dec 5, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Roger Quilter - Subjects: Christmas letter; pleased with Bobby; likes his new house
Dec 6, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: saw Grande Illusion with Langers; woman visits whose mother's name was Rosina Grace Hubley; Jacques is engaged
Dec 7, 1938 - To: Wilfrid - From: Hetty - Subjects: Bancel loved their notes on his father's death; Hetty expecting in June
Dec 9, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Cynthia in hospital; Bobby likes film of Idiot's Delight (not yet released); Abe Lincoln book in January
Dec 15, 1938 - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Susie and Lilli; Bay; Schley's cousin is Mrs. Dick Whitney; Madeleine's Christmas party; tomorrow to see Abe Lincoln; Kate and Gerry expecting; Langers to Cynthia's for Christmas; Susie and Mox Kobbe to see Oscar Wilde
Dec 25, [1938?] - To: Lydia - From: Agnes Brady - Subject: her daughter Retta
Dec 27, [1938] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Ros ill; Langers; Christmas eve with Bob and Madeleine; Winty's daughter Daphne; Lydia Sherwood Williams pregnant
Dec 28, 1938 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Christmas activities; Alexander Woollcott broadcast; Edith Olivier's book
Jan 2, 1939 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Dinah wants Jane to paint Brett twins--Jane gives money to Jewish refugees; Roger and the Marshes; saw film The Great Waltz
Jan 13, [1939] - To: E.L.M. (Cheyne Walk) - From: Lydia Sherwood Williams (145 E. 74th) - Subjects: saw Maurice Evans in Hamlet; Neville in Rome; Doughty Washburn engaged
Feb 1, 1939 - To: Lydia - From: Secretary to Mrs. Roosevelt's secretary - Subject: hanging of Mrs. Hoover's portrait
Feb 9, [1939] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subject: Lydia and Bill to Century Club to see Bellows' paintings; Ros is with Shepards in Palm Beach; Winty sends salary to Marian; Bobby in Rio
Feb 13, 1939 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: anti-New Deal literature from Lydia who hates FDR; Franco; Wilfrid has painful leg
[Feb 1939] - To: Jane - From: Posie - Subjects: Langers for lunch and said goodbye; Bob and Madeleine went to S. America a week ago--Rio, Montevideo, Buenos Aires; Playwrights Company; Dramatists Guild; Bill's Mercury Process is being used on a ship
Feb 24, 1939 - To: Lydia - From: Helen H. Hazard - Subject: Lydia's portrait of their children
Feb 22, 1939 - To: Posie - From: Ros (in Palm Beach) - Subjects: with the Shepards; dinner with Leroy King, Prince Alexis Obelensky, Lupe Velez, Lili Damita, and Woolworth Donahue
Feb 24, 1939 - To: Lydia - From: Jane - Subjects: Rachel lives at Overshot?; Grinke trio; Florence Hooton; saw Duck Soup; Guy in Egypt
Feb 25, [1939] - To: Jane - From: Lydia - Subjects: Dorothy Thompson goes too far; Lillian Herson; Eden is out, Chamberlain's peace; Simpsons and Windsors; Bermuda--Herm, Helen, Kate, Rob, Ros; brother Bill; Susie has bronchitis; Snow White at Radio City; Toscanini; Conquest starring Garbo and Boyer; share Suez with Mussolini